<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://mini2dx.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://mini2dx.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-14T18:40:01+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/</id><title type="html">mini2Dx</title><subtitle>mini2Dx is an open-source beginner-friendly, master-ready framework for rapidly prototyping and building 2D games in Java.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.3 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2018/07/14/mini2Dx-1-7-3-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.7.3 released" /><published>2018-07-14T17:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-14T17:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2018/07/14/mini2Dx-1-7-3-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2018/07/14/mini2Dx-1-7-3-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.7.3 has been released with a fix to using the defer() method multiple times on a UiElement in one update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.3 has been released with a fix to using the defer() method multiple times on a UiElement in one update. To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.2 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/23/mini2Dx-1-7-2-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.7.2 released" /><published>2018-06-23T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-23T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/23/mini2Dx-1-7-2-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/23/mini2Dx-1-7-2-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.7.2 has been released with a large number of memory usage improvements across all the geometry classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.2 has been released with a large number of memory usage improvements across all the geometry classes. To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.1 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/12/mini2Dx-1-7-1-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.7.1 released" /><published>2018-06-12T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-12T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/12/mini2Dx-1-7-1-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/12/mini2Dx-1-7-1-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.7.1 has been released to add an additional method to the TypingTextAnimation API for retrieving the current character index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.1 has been released to add an additional method to the TypingTextAnimation API for retrieving the current character index. To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0 released and the roadmap ahead</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/10/mini2Dx-1-7-0-released-and-roadmap-ahead.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.7.0 released and the roadmap ahead" /><published>2018-06-10T15:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-10T15:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/10/mini2Dx-1-7-0-released-and-roadmap-ahead</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2018/06/10/mini2Dx-1-7-0-released-and-roadmap-ahead.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;170&quot;&gt;1.7.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several months work, I’m happy to announce the release of mini2Dx 1.7.0. This release comes with a lot of bug fixes, optimisations and improvements. You can find the full list in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/blob/master/CHANGES&quot;&gt;CHANGES file&lt;/a&gt; on the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that 1.7.0 is released, it’s time to talk about the future of mini2Dx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Apple deprecated OpenGL on Mac. This means that at some point in the future, the current version of mini2Dx will stop working as it is tightly coupled to OpenGL via LibGDX. While I’m disappointed in this decision from Apple, I still want game developers using mini2Dx to be able to release on Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I’m hoping to bring my next mini2Dx-based game &lt;a href=&quot;https://alchemiccutie.com&quot;&gt;Alchemic Cutie&lt;/a&gt; to consoles - this means that using a JRE-based environemt won’t be possible. However, I like coding games in Java and would like to continue to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that, I’m beginning work on the next generation of mini2Dx - 2.0! The goal of the next generation is to support more platforms such as web browsers and consoles. Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Core API will consist mostly of interfaces to platform implementations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desktop will use two runtimes; the current LibGDX runtime and eventually a bgfx runtime&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android/iOS will continue to use the LibGDX runtime&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web support will also be added via the LibGDX runtime&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Console support will be added via MonoGame and cross-compilation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This development will take a lot of time and won’t be completed until 2019. In the meantime, you can expect that I’ll keep supporting 1.7.x of mini2Dx with fixes. All 1.7.x development will continue in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx-ve&quot;&gt;mini2Dx Vintage Edition&lt;/a&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an existing mini2Dx user, you’re probably wondering what this means for your current game. My goal is to keep the 2.0 API as close as possible to the existing 1.7.x API (since I’m also implementing a game against 1.7.x). So there may be a small number of method changes needed during the upgrade but you can expect the same functionality to be available and more!
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">1.7.0 After several months work, I’m happy to announce the release of mini2Dx 1.7.0. This release comes with a lot of bug fixes, optimisations and improvements. You can find the full list in the CHANGES file on the repository. To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page. Roadmap Now that 1.7.0 is released, it’s time to talk about the future of mini2Dx. Recently, Apple deprecated OpenGL on Mac. This means that at some point in the future, the current version of mini2Dx will stop working as it is tightly coupled to OpenGL via LibGDX. While I’m disappointed in this decision from Apple, I still want game developers using mini2Dx to be able to release on Mac. Furthermore, I’m hoping to bring my next mini2Dx-based game Alchemic Cutie to consoles - this means that using a JRE-based environemt won’t be possible. However, I like coding games in Java and would like to continue to do so. So with that, I’m beginning work on the next generation of mini2Dx - 2.0! The goal of the next generation is to support more platforms such as web browsers and consoles. Here’s how: Core API will consist mostly of interfaces to platform implementations Desktop will use two runtimes; the current LibGDX runtime and eventually a bgfx runtime Android/iOS will continue to use the LibGDX runtime Web support will also be added via the LibGDX runtime Console support will be added via MonoGame and cross-compilation This development will take a lot of time and won’t be completed until 2019. In the meantime, you can expect that I’ll keep supporting 1.7.x of mini2Dx with fixes. All 1.7.x development will continue in the mini2Dx Vintage Edition repository. As an existing mini2Dx user, you’re probably wondering what this means for your current game. My goal is to keep the 2.0 API as close as possible to the existing 1.7.x API (since I’m also implementing a game against 1.7.x). So there may be a small number of method changes needed during the upgrade but you can expect the same functionality to be available and more!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.4 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/29/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.4-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.4 released" /><published>2017-10-29T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-29T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/29/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.4-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/29/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.4-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.4 has now been released to Maven Central which removes the requirement for prototype beans to have setters/getters for dependency injection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.4 has now been released to Maven Central which removes the requirement for prototype beans to have setters/getters for dependency injection. To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.3 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/28/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.3-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.3 released" /><published>2017-10-28T15:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-10-28T15:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/28/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.3-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/28/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.3-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.3 has now been released to Maven Central which adds the following fixes and improvements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(#74) Added TiledMapLoader for loading TiledMap instances via AssetManager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added #equals method to ControllerButton implementations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed dependency injection validating injection too early&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.3 has now been released to Maven Central which adds the following fixes and improvements: (#74) Added TiledMapLoader for loading TiledMap instances via AssetManager Added #equals method to ControllerButton implementations Fixed dependency injection validating injection too early To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.2 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/22/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.2-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.2 released" /><published>2017-10-22T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-10-22T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/22/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.2-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/22/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.2-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.2 has now been released to Maven Central which includes several fixes and test coverage improvements thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CauchyAbel&quot;&gt;Ben Xiao (CauchyAbel)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added jacocoTestReport for better code coverage reporting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed incorrect Circle bounding box dimensions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed merging concurrency exception during object movement within concurrent QuadTrees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(#53) Increased code coverage on Rectangle and Circle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added Sprite#getAlpha() method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.2 has now been released to Maven Central which includes several fixes and test coverage improvements thanks to Ben Xiao (CauchyAbel). Added jacocoTestReport for better code coverage reporting Fixed incorrect Circle bounding box dimensions Fixed merging concurrency exception during object movement within concurrent QuadTrees (#53) Increased code coverage on Rectangle and Circle Added Sprite#getAlpha() method To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.1 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/10/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.1-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.1 released" /><published>2017-10-10T22:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-10-10T22:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/10/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.1-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2017/10/10/mini2Dx-1-7-0-beta.1-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.1 has now been released to Maven Central which begins work on improving the UI framework for more complex UIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This beta includes the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added new FlexDirections; ROW_REVERSE and CENTER&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[BREAKING]&lt;/strong&gt; LayoutRuleset is now applied to both horizontal and vertical calculations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[BREAKING]&lt;/strong&gt; UI minHeight now includes padding + margin in check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.7.0-beta.1 has now been released to Maven Central which begins work on improving the UI framework for more complex UIs. This beta includes the following changes: Added new FlexDirections; ROW_REVERSE and CENTER [BREAKING] LayoutRuleset is now applied to both horizontal and vertical calculations [BREAKING] UI minHeight now includes padding + margin in check To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.6.5 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2017/09/30/mini2Dx-1-6-5-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.6.5 released" /><published>2017-09-30T15:55:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-30T15:55:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2017/09/30/mini2Dx-1-6-5-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2017/09/30/mini2Dx-1-6-5-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.6.5 has now been released to Maven Central which fixes support for flipped tiles in Tiled object GID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.6.5 has now been released to Maven Central which fixes support for flipped tiles in Tiled object GID. To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">mini2Dx 1.6.4 released</title><link href="http://mini2dx.org/2017/09/15/mini2Dx-1-6-4-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="mini2Dx 1.6.4 released" /><published>2017-09-15T20:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-15T20:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://mini2dx.org/2017/09/15/mini2Dx-1-6-4-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mini2dx.org/2017/09/15/mini2Dx-1-6-4-released.html">&lt;p&gt;mini2Dx 1.6.4 has now been released to Maven Central and includes two important fixes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed child UI elements receiving mouseDown events when hidden&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed API regression - missing setCenter method in shapes (caused by 1.3 refactor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update your existing projects, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mini2Dx/mini2Dx/wiki/Updating-mini2Dx&quot;&gt;Updating mini2Dx&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thomas Cashman</name></author><summary type="html">mini2Dx 1.6.4 has now been released to Maven Central and includes two important fixes: Fixed child UI elements receiving mouseDown events when hidden Fixed API regression - missing setCenter method in shapes (caused by 1.3 refactor) To update your existing projects, see the Updating mini2Dx wiki page.</summary></entry></feed>